<?xml version='1.0'?> 
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
          "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY manrevision "0.2"> 
  <!ENTITY date "July 2006"> 
  <!ENTITY appversion "4.3.90.2"> 
  <!ENTITY app "<application>orage</application>">
]>

<article id="orage" lang="en">

<!-- Header --> 
<articleinfo>

  <title>Orage</title>

  <copyright>
    <year>2005-2006</year> <holder>Mickael Graf</holder>
  </copyright>

<!-- translators: uncomment this:

  <copyright>
   <year>2002</year> <holder>ME-THE-TRANSLATOR (Latin
   translation)</holder>
  </copyright>

 -->

<!-- I don't know about this
  <legalnotice id="legalnotice">
    <para>
      This document is provided under the terms of the GNU GPL, version
      2 or (at your option) any later version.
    </para>
  </legalnotice>
-->
  <authorgroup>

    <author>
      <firstname>Mickael</firstname> <surname>Graf</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <address><email>korbinus@xfce.org</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

    <author>
      <firstname>Juha</firstname> <surname>Kautto</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <address><email>juha@xfce.org</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

    <author>
      <firstname>Benedikt</firstname> <surname>Meurer</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <address><email>benny@xfce.org</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

    <author>
      <firstname>Edscott Wilson</firstname> <surname>Garcia</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <address><email>edscott@xfce.org</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

<!-- This is appropriate place for other contributors: translators,
maintainers, etc. Commented out by default.

    <othercredit role="translator">
      <firstname>Latin</firstname> <surname>Translator 1</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <orgname>Latin Translation Team</orgname>
        <address><email>translator@gnome.org</email> </address>
      </affiliation> <contrib>Latin translation</contrib>
    </othercredit>
-->

  </authorgroup>

  <!--
  <revhistory>
    <revision>
      <revnumber>0.4</revnumber> 
      <date>May 2003</date>
      <authorinitials>jbh</authorinitials>
    </revision>
    <revision>
      <revnumber>0.3</revnumber> 
      <date>February 2003</date>
      <authorinitials>jbh</authorinitials>
    </revision>
  </revhistory>
  -->

  <releaseinfo>This manual describes &app; version &appversion;.
    Last updated: &date;
  </releaseinfo>

</articleinfo>

  <!-- extra space -->
  <para>&nbsp;</para>
  
<sect1 id="orage-intro">
  <title>Introduction</title>

  <para>
    Orage is a time-managing application that is part of the
    <ulink url="http://www.xfce.org" type="html">Xfce 4 Desktop Environment
    </ulink> and features a calendar window, lists of events and reminders.
    It also provides an easy way to archive and manage your old appointments.
  </para>

</sect1>

  <!-- extra space -->
  <para>&nbsp;</para>
  
<sect1 id="orage-getting-started">
  <title>Getting started</title>

  <para>
    Orage is started by typing &app; on the command line or in the run
    application window. You can also start it by clicking on the item &app;
    in the submenu "Office" from the desktop menu.
    Another handy way of starting &app; is to click button 1 on orageclock
    panel plugin.
  </para>
  <para>
    But actually the first thing you should do is to adjust your 
    <link linkend="orage-preferences-window">preferences</link>. At least
    before adding any appointments, you should set your local
    <link linkend="preferences-timezone-tab">timezone</link>.
  </para>

  <figure id="desktop-menuitem-fig">
    <title>Orage menu item in the desktop menu</title>
    <screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/orage_desktop_menuitem.png" 
                     format="PNG" />
        </imageobject>
        <!--
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/orage_desktop_menuitem.eps" format="EPS" />
        </imageobject>
        -->
        <textobject>
          <phrase>
            For starting &app; from the desktop menu: "Office" and then click
            on "Orage".
          </phrase>
        </textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>

  <para>
    When you run &app;, you will first see the calendar window appearing.
  </para>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-calendar-window">
  <title>The calendar window</title>
  <figure id="default-calendar-fig">
    <title>Default Calendar window</title>

    <screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/default_calendar.png" format="PNG" />
        </imageobject>
        <!--
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/default_calendar.eps" format="EPS" />
        </imageobject>
        -->
        <textobject>
          <phrase>
            The calendar window.
          </phrase>
        </textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>

  <para>
    The calendar window provides you a menu bar giving access to different
    functions. 
    Below that is a nice calendar showing the month, the year, day names,
    week numbers. 
  </para>

  <sect2 id="calendar-menu-bar">
    <title>The menu bar</title>
    <para>
      The menubar contains four menus, which are the File, Edit, View, Help.
    </para>

    <sect3 id="calendar-file-menu">
      <title>The File menu</title>

      <figure id="calendar-file-menu-fig">
        <title>File menu in the calendar window</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/orage_calendar_file_menu.png" 
                         format="PNG" />
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
              <phrase>
                The File menu in the calendar window.
              </phrase>
            </textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>
      </figure>

      <para>
        The file menu contains five items:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>New: fire an appointment window (see below) for creating a
                  new appointment;
        </listitem>
        <listitem>Open archive file...: fire a file selector for opening file
                  containing old items;
                  <warning>
                    <para>
                      This makes the selected file to act as your current 
                      active calendar file. It is possible to add, modify and 
                      remove appointments from it. You probably only want to 
                      take a look and return to your normal file (by closing 
                      archive file). 
                    </para>
                  </warning>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>Close archive file: close the previously opened file -
                  greyed when no file opened;
        </listitem>
        <listitem>Close: close the calendar window, keeping the application
                  running;
        </listitem>
        <listitem>Quit: close the opened windows and end the application;
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 id="calendar-edit-menu">
      <title>The Edit menu</title>

      <figure id="calendar-edit-menu-fig">
        <title>Edit menu in the calendar window</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/orage_calendar_edit_menu.png"
                         format="PNG" />
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
              <phrase>
                The Edit menu in the calendar window.
              </phrase>
            </textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>
      </figure>

      <para>
        The Edit menu gives you access to the setting window, which will be
        presented later on.
      </para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 id="calendar-view-menu">
      <title>The View menu</title>

      <figure id="calendar-view-menu-fig">
        <title>View menu in the calendar window</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/orage_calendar_view_menu.png"
                         format="PNG" />
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
              <phrase>
                The View menu in the calendar window.
              </phrase>
            </textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>
      </figure>

      <para>
        The View menu has two choices:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>View selected date: show the event list of currently
                  selected date;
        </listitem>
        <listitem>Select today: set calendar's selected day to be today;
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 id="calendar-help-menu">
      <title>The Help menu</title>

      <figure id="calendar-help-menu-fig">
        <title>Help menu in the calendar window</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/orage_calendar_help_menu.png"
                         format="PNG" />
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
              <phrase>
                The Help menu in the calendar window.
              </phrase>
            </textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>
      </figure>

      <para>
        The Help menu has also two choices:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>Help: show this help file;</listitem>
        <listitem>About: show information about the authors and license;
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="calendar-window">
    <title>The calendar</title>

    <para>
      Calendar view presents you one month, which you can change by pressing
      the arrow beside the month name or the year number or using the mouse 
      wheel.
      Days where you have appointments are marked as bold. One day is always
      selected and shown with a block.
      You can change the selected day by single clicking any day number.
      Double clicking a day number causes event-list window for that day to be
      activated.
    </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-eventlist-window">
  <title>The eventlist window</title>

  <figure id="orage-eventlist-fig">
    <title>Orage eventlist window</title>
    <screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/orage_eventlist.png" format="PNG" />
        </imageobject>
        <textobject>
          <phrase>
            The eventlist window.
          </phrase>
        </textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>

  <para>
    The eventlist (or appointment list as it is also called) window shows all
    activites that you have reserved for the day (date is shown in the window
    heading the format yyyy-mm-dd).
    On top of the window it gives you buttons to do actions. (All actions are
    also available in menus above the buttons.)
    This is your main activity window and you may want to keep it up all the
    day and even make it to appear on all workspaces or to be always on top
    of other windows.
  </para>

  <sect2 id="eventlist-action-bar">
    <title>The button bar</title>
    <para>
      There are 9 activity buttons in the button bar from left to right:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>New: start an <link linkend="orage-appointment-window">
                appointment window</link> for creating a new appointment for 
                this day;
      </listitem>
      <listitem>Back: show previous day; </listitem>
      <listitem>Today: show today; </listitem>
      <listitem>Forward: show next day; </listitem>
      <listitem>Refresh: Redisplay this date. This window is usually 
        refreshed automatically, but on certain special cases it may
        not show the latest changes. (Most common case is probably
        when you start editing an appointment from the alarm window
        instead from this eventlist window);
      </listitem>
      <listitem>Duplicate: start an <ulink url="#orage-appointment-window">
        appointment window</ulink> for creating a new appointment for
        this day. But do not start from scratch, but copy all values
        from the active row in the appointment list below. Note that
        if you do not have any rows selected from the eventlist, this
        button does not do anything (but gives a g_warning, which you
        normally cannot see);
      </listitem>
      <listitem>Close: close this window; </listitem>
      <listitem>Clear: remove all appointments which start on the shown day.
        Note that it is possible to create repeating appointments in
        &app; and if such an appointment is shown, but starts on an
        earlier date, it is NOT removed. (But repeating events will
        be removed if the first day is on this day.) Be carefull with
        this button! Before removing anything it asks for your
        verification, because it may remove many appointments.
        (Note that you can not delete a single appointment in this
        window; you have to go to the appointment window to do that);
      </listitem>
      <listitem>Day count: you can see more than one day in this window by
        setting this number to larger than 0. Each number means show
        one more day. (It causes the Time column in the event
        listing to show also the date.) Note however that each
        repeating appointment is shown only once (=first time)
        instead of everytime it happens.
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="eventlist-appointments">
    <title>The eventlist</title>
    <para>
      The event list shows all appointments happening on this day.  Scrollbars
      will appear if there are more lines or longer lines than what can fit
      into the window.  You can edit any appointment by double clicking the
      row. Each line has three fields:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        Time: the starting and ending times of the appointment (it shows the
        date only if more than one day is shown). If the event has passed, it
        is overstriked. Currently active appointments are shown with red
        colour and future appointments are bold. It is also possible to define
        special whole day appoinmtments and they always have a text "All day"
        instead of real start and end times.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Flags: gives information about the appointment. (Note that the
        explanations are visible as a hint when you move your cursor into the
        event list.) There are three flags in order:
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            Alarm: what kind of action happens when alarm time passes.
            <keycap>n</keycap> means no alarm has been defined.
            <keycap>A</keycap> means that window is raised as an alarm and
            <keycap>S</keycap> means that in addition to the window, a
            sound is also played.
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            Repeat: how often is that appointment happening.
            <keycap>n</keycap> means no repeating so that this event only
            happens once. <keycap>D</keycap> means daily repeat,
            <keycap>W</keycap> weekly, <keycap>M</keycap> monthly and
            <keycap>Y</keycap> yearly.
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            Type: what kind of reservation is this. Two options:
            <keycap>f</keycap> means free so that the action is not reserving
            the time and it is possible to schedule more appointments at the
            same time and respectively <keycap>B</keycap> means busy, so that
            nothing else can not be done at this time.  Note that current
            version of &app; does not enforce these and the flag is only as a
            comment (in the future this may be enforced).
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Title: the heading of the appointment. Note that the whole title is
        shown, so you may want to avoid using too long titles to keep the view
        cleaner.
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-appointment-window">
  <title>The appointment window</title>

  <para>
    The appointment window is used to add, edit and delete appointments.
    It is the most complex window in &app;, but most fields still have good
    default values and are not mandatory. It has button bar (All actions are
    also available in menus above the buttons) and three tabs controlling
    basic settings and alarms and recurrence settings.
  </para>

  <sect2 id="appointment-action-bar">
    <title>The button bar</title>
    <para>
      There are 5 activity buttons in the button bar from left to right:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>Save: store the appointment to the orage system. This causes
        also data validity checking.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>Save and close: like Save, but also closes the window.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>Revert: undo all changes done after previous save. Note that
        this button is active only after data has been changed.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>Duplicate: start creating new appointment and copy all values
        from the current activity into it. The new appointment is not created
        until you press <guibutton>Save</guibutton>.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>Delete: remove current appointment permanently from orage
        system.
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="appointment-general-tab">
    <title>The general tab</title>

    <figure id="orage-appointment-fig">
      <title>Orage appointment window - general tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_appointment.png" format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The appointment window.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <para>
      In this tab, you define the contents of the appointment.
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Title</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>The title of the appointment. It appears in the event list
            and also in the alarm window and is listed at the header of this
            window. It should be a rather short summary of the appointment.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Location</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>This field should describe where the event happens. It can
            be for example Home or Office or Paris depending on what kind of
            appointment you have. It is also possible to leave it empty. &app;
            is not using it in any special way, nor is it visible anywhere 
            else than here.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="all-day-event">All day event</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Selecting this checkbox causes so called whole day appointment
            to be defined. These do not have start nor end time defined, but
            it is possible that the event lasts several days. These are 
            special since they always have window type alarm defined and 
            although it is possible to add separate alarm (in alarm tab), it 
            is ignored and not even stored to the system. (no warning is given
            so this is a bit confusing.) The automatic alarm is raised when
            &app; is started or date changes and the new day has this kind of
            event.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Start</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Defines the start time of the appointment. First, press the    
            date button and choose the date from the calendar. After that
            you set the hour and minute using either your mouse wheel or
            clicking the small arrows. It is also possible to type the
            numbers directly to the fields. Hours go from 0 to 23 (24 is not
            allowed value).
          </para>
          <para>The last button is timezone. Default value for new
            appointments is your current timezone, which you have set in the
            preferences. It is recommended to use real timezones instead of
            floating. You should not mix floating with real timezones although 
            it is possible. Floating means that time is not bound to any
            timezone, but varies according to current settings. Modifying
            either the default timezone or start timezone may cause floating
            values to change.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>End</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Similar to Start, but defines naturally the ending time. Note
            that start and end timezones may be different (for example when
            you schedule a meeting in abroad you can set the starting time in
            your local timezone and the rest of the timings in thedestination
            timezone).
            <link linkend="orage-eventlist-window"> Eventlist window</link>
            always shows times in your local time.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Duration</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Often it is easier to set the appointment duration instead of
            ending time. You can do that by marking the first box here. It is
            not possible to have both end time and duration at the same time,
            so end time setting will be unavailable after you select duration.
            Maximum duration is 1000 days, which is almost three years. Note
            that although the minute selectionm jumps 5 minutes at a time, you
            can manually enter any number (just remember to tab out from the
            field, so that the value is read).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Availability</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>What kind of reservation is this. There are two possiblities:
            <emphasis>Free</emphasis> means that the action is not reserving
            the time and it is possible to schedule more appointments at the
            same time and respectively <emphasis>Busy</emphasis> means that
            nothing else can not be done at this time.  Note that current
            version of &app; does not enforce these menings and the flag is
            only as a comment (in the future this may be checked).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Note</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Free format long text, where you can and should explain more
            the appointment. It is shown in the alarm window.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="appointment-alarm-tab">
    <title>The alarm tab</title>

    <figure id="orage-appointment-alarm-fig">
      <title>Orage appointment window - alarm tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_appointment_alarm.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The appointment alarm tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <para>
      In this tab, you define the alarm for the appointment. &app; supports 
      two kinds of alarms: window and sound, but they both happen at the same 
      time and sound is just an extra alarm; it is not possible to only raise
      sound alarm. window alarm is raised if any of the alarm timing numbers
      is non zero (in other words there is no special flag to set alarm; just 
      define the time for it). Similarly sound alarm is raised if sound file
      has a value.
    </para>
    <para>NOTE: this alarm setting has no effect on 
        <link linkend="all-day-event">all day events</link>; they always
        have only window type alarm set.
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Alarm</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Define how much earlier (compared to the appointment starting
            time) the alarm(s) happens. If all numbers are zero, no alarm is
            raised for this appointment.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Sound</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Define the sound file to be played when the alarm fires.
            Leaving this empty disables sound alarm and putting any value
            enables it. Remember to define the actual play command in the
            preferences dialog. You should also test that your system can 
            play the filetype you choose there. Simply start a terminal and
            test it using the command you specified and the the sound file.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Repeat alarm sound</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Set this check box if you want to hear the sound more than
            once. (Usually you want to check this.) Note that there is an
            internal counter, which stops the sound after 500 plays. Note
            also that when sound is repeating it is restarted after each 2
            seconds, so you may get problems with longer lasting soundfiles.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="appointment-recurrence-tab">
    <title>The recurrence tab</title>

    <figure id="orage-appointment-recurrence-fig">
      <title>Orage appointment window - recurrence tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_appointment_recurrence.png"
                     format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The appointment recurrence tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <para>
      In this tab you can define repeating appointments. Sometimes it makes
      much sense to define that the same appointment happens every day or
      every month instead of creating a new appoointment for each event.
    </para>
    <para>
      First you need to select <emphasis>recurrence</emphasis> period. Default
      is no repeat and other possibilities are daily, weekly, monthly and
      yearly.
    </para>
    <para>
      &app; allows you also to limit the repeating count:
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>Repeat forever: this is default and does not limit the
          number of occurrences.
        </listitem>
        <listitem>Repeat n times: the appointment is scheduled exactly n
          times. After that it ends (but is not removed).
        </listitem>
        <listitem>Repeat until date: you can select the last date when this
          event happens. Note that it still happens normally during this date.
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-preferences-window">
  <title>The preferences window</title>

  <para>
    The preferences window is used to enter initial values for &app;.
    You can define several display options, how old apppointments should
    be archived and what is the play command to be used for playing sound
    alarms and also you can set the local timezone for &app;.
  </para>

  <sect2 id="preferences-display-tab">
    <title>The display tab</title>

    <figure id="orage-preferences-display-fig">
      <title>Orage preferences window - display tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_preferences_display.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The preferences display tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <para>
      In this tab you can define visibility options for the 
      <link linkend="orage-calendar-window">main window</link> of &app;.
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Calendar borders</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>You can hide window borders and make the calendar window 
            smaller by choosing Hidden option. This frees more space to your 
            other applicatiosn from your workspace.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Calendar window</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>This option defines where the main window is visible.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Calendar start</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>It is possible to define that &app; starts in the background
            or as minimized. This option only affects the start of &app;.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="preferences-archives-tab">
    <title>The archives tab</title>

    <figure id="orage-preferences-archives-fig">
      <title>Orage preferences window - archives tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_preferences_archives.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The preferences archives tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <para>
      &app; does not delete appointments automatically, so usually your
      calendar file grows bigger and because of that &app; gets slower and
      takes up more memory from the system. It is possible to define
      automatic archiving so that old appointments are moved from the active
      calendar file to passive history file. This helps to keep the active
      file smaller and the application in good shape. Archiving is enabled by
      setting the threshold to other than "never" value. Of course it is also
      possible to manually delete appointments, but that removes them 
      permanently and you will not be able to find them later.
    </para>
    <para>
      Unfortunately &app; version &appversion; has no way to search or bring
      back appointments from the history file. This means that although the
      archived events are not lost, they vanish so that you can only access
      them with the not so perfect
      <link linkend="calendar-file-menu">archive file</link>
      method (or manually outside &app;).
    </para>
    <para>
      Note that &app; also splits
      <link linkend="appointment-recurrence-tab">recurring appointments</link>
      so that if the original start date is older than threshold, that
      appointment is added to the archive file and the starting date in the
      active calendar file is updated to contain only values more recent than
      threshold. This also saves time when &app; is searching recurrent
      events.
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Archive file</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>This file will contain the archived appointments. It will
            grow, but since &app; is not accessing it, that does not matter.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Archive threshold</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>This enables archiving mode by setting it to other than 
            "never" value. Choises are 3, 6 or 12 months.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="preferences-sound-tab">
    <title>The sound tab</title>

    <figure id="orage-preferences-sound-fig">
      <title>Orage preferences window - sound tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_preferences_sound.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The preferences sound tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <para>
      In this tab you can define which sound command &app; uses when playing
      sound files. try testing some common commands like play or aplay 
      from terminal to see what works in your system. You probably do not want
      to use full version of totem or mplayer since they will cause a video
      window also to appear and that most probably is not what you want.
    </para>
    <para>
      Basically it is possible to do other than sound commands also since 
      &app; really only starts this program and gives it
      <link linkend="appointment-alarm-tab">the sound file</link>
      as parameter. But this is not the intention of this feature.
    </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="preferences-timezone-tab">
    <title>The timezone tab</title>

    <figure id="orage-preferences-timezone-fig">
      <title>Orage preferences window - timezone tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_preferences_timezone.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The preferences timezone tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <para>
      You should always set the default timezone for &app; It is possible to
      use also floating times, but then all times should be in floating form.
      It definitely is a bad idea to mix floating and timezone times. 
      Floating times tend to move to follow any timezones they see...
    </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-undocumented">
  <title>Undocumented Features</title>
  <para>
    Some hidden options allow you to customize &app; behaviour. You can find 
    and change those in
    <filename>~/.config/xfce4/orage/oragerc</filename>. (note that the active 
    calendar file is also localeted in this directory.) You must be carefull 
    not to change the format of these files or &app; may not start anymore.
    Undocumented settings are:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      Main Window Position: normally you do not want to change this. It is the
      location of <link linkend="orage-calendar-window">calendar window</link>
      in the screen. &app; updates this automatically, so your setting will be
      overwritten.
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      Event Window Size: normally you do not want to change this. It is the
      size of <link linkend="orage-eventlist-window">eventlist window</link>
      in the screen. &app; updates this automatically, so your setting will be
      overwritten.
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      Show Main Window Menu: setting this to 0 causes the menubar from
      <link linkend="orage-calendar-window">calendar window</link> to vanish.
      If you never use the menu, you can save screenspace with this and using
      <link linkend="preferences-display-tab">Calendar border option</link>. 
      Default value is 1 (=show the menu). Only 0 and 1 are valid values.
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      Select Always Today: controls which day is selected after &app; main
      <link linkend="orage-calendar-window">calendar window</link> is hidden
      and comes visible again (for example clicking orageclock panel plugin).
      Default value is 0, which means that previously selected day will remain
      selected. The other option is 1, which causes current date always being
      selected. Only 0 and 1 are valid values.
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      Use Dynamic Icon: setting these x and y sizes to nonzero causes &app; 
      to use dynamic icon, which has real month day number in it. It also
      lists &app; in the top and month name at the bottom if those fit in.
      &app; tries to fit all those three pieces of information in the available
      icon size using proper fonts, but if there is not enough space, top and
      bottom texts can be omitted. Finally &app; switches to static icon if
      not even the number fits into the icon. Good values to test with are 32
      (like X=32 Y=32).
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-faq">
  <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>

  <para>
    Some common questions and answers.
  </para>
  <qandadiv><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>
          Why does my week start on Saturday?
        </para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>
          This really is a problem in your distro. You can check how your
          operating system reports these to GTK+ and hence to &app;, which
          uses strictly gtk calendar widget and does not tune these settings
          itself. Command <command>locale first_weekday</command> shows
          which day is the first day in your system. Usually Sunday is day
          number 1, but that can be changed so check that with command
          <command>locale day</command>, which shows days starting from day 
          number 1. You may try with different LANG enevironment variable
          settings and calendar view in &app; should change accordingly. Log
          a new bug for &app; if you think it is not working correctly.
          Look more information from
          <ulink url="http://bugzilla.xfce.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1237" 
                 type="html">Xfce bug 1237
          </ulink>
          or from
          <ulink url="http://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=215466"
                 type="html">Debian bug 215466
          </ulink>
        </para>
        <para>
          If you are adventurous, you can actually fix these yourself. You
          need to find your locale definition file (like fi_FI or fr_FR). 
          <command>locate</command> is your friend here and helps finding it.
          After that you can check what the setting is: 
          <command>grep first_weekday fi_FI</command> and change that if it is
          wrong and after that you need to recompile your locale database.
        </para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>
          How can I insert my ical file into &app;?
        </para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>
          This is not currently possible. It is planned in future versions.
        </para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>
          I have found a bug in &app; or would like to see a new feature. How
          can I inform that to the developers?
        </para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>
          You should file a bug into
          <ulink url="http://bugzilla.xfce.org/" 
                 type="html">Xfce bugzilla
          </ulink>
          send an email to 
        <email>xfce4-dev@xfce.org</email> Xfce development.
        </para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
  </qandadiv>
</sect1>
<!--
<appendix><title>An Appendix</title>
<para>...</para>
</appendix>
-->
</article>
