<?xml version='1.0'?> 
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
          "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY manrevision "1.5"> 
  <!ENTITY date "July 2008"> 
  <!ENTITY appversion "4.5.13"> 
  <!ENTITY app "<application>orage</application>">
]>

<article id="orage" lang="en">

<!-- Header --> 
<articleinfo>

  <title>Orage</title>
  <copyright>
    <year>2006-2008</year> <holder>Juha Kautto</holder>
  </copyright>

<!-- translators: uncomment this:

  <copyright>
   <year>2002</year> <holder>ME-THE-TRANSLATOR (Latin
   translation)</holder>
  </copyright>

 -->

<!-- I don't know about this
  <legalnotice id="legalnotice">
    <para>
      This document is provided under the terms of the GNU GPL, version
      2 or (at your option) any later version.
    </para>
  </legalnotice>
-->
  <authorgroup>
    <author>
      <firstname>Juha</firstname> <surname>Kautto</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <address><email>juha@xfce.org</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <firstname>Mickael</firstname> <surname>Graf</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <address><email>korbinus@xfce.org</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <firstname>Benedikt</firstname> <surname>Meurer</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <address><email>benny@xfce.org</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>
<!-- This is appropriate place for other contributors: translators,
maintainers, etc. Commented out by default.

    <othercredit role="translator">
      <firstname>Latin</firstname> <surname>Translator 1</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <orgname>Latin Translation Team</orgname>
        <address><email>translator@gnome.org</email> </address>
      </affiliation> <contrib>Latin translation</contrib>
    </othercredit>
-->
  </authorgroup>

  <!--
  <revhistory>
    <revision>
      <revnumber>0.4</revnumber> 
      <date>May 2003</date>
      <authorinitials>jbh</authorinitials>
    </revision>
    <revision>
      <revnumber>0.3</revnumber> 
      <date>February 2003</date>
      <authorinitials>jbh</authorinitials>
    </revision>
  </revhistory>
  -->

  <releaseinfo>This manual describes &app; version &appversion;.
    Last updated: &date;
  </releaseinfo>

</articleinfo>

  <!-- extra space -->
  <para>&nbsp;</para>
  
<sect1 id="orage-intro">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <para>
    Orage is a time-managing application of the
    <ulink url="http://www.xfce.org" type="html">Xfce 4 Desktop Environment
    </ulink>. It includes a calendar window, list of events and day view.
    Orage has several kinds of alarms and is ical compatible so that you can
    transfer appointments from other calendar systems into Orage or vica versa.
    It also provides an easy way to archive and manage your old appointments.
  </para>
</sect1>

  <!-- extra space -->
  <para>&nbsp;</para>
  
<sect1 id="orage-getting-started">
  <title>Getting started</title>
  <para>
    Orage is started by typing &app; on the command line or in the run
    application window. The command line accepts some optins like -v, which
    tells the version and -h, which shows short usage help. You can also start
    &app; by clicking on the item &app; in the submenu "Office" from the
    desktop menu. Another handy way of starting &app; is to click button 1 on
    orageclock panel plugin. But usually &app; is started automatically as
    part of Xfce startup.
  </para>
  <para>
    The first thing you should do is to adjust your 
    <link linkend="orage-preferences-window">preferences</link>. 
    Before adding any appointments, it is strongly recommended to set your
    local <link linkend="preferences-main-tab">timezone</link>.
  </para>

  <figure id="desktop-menuitem-fig">
    <title>Orage menu item in the desktop menu</title>
    <screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/orage_desktop_menuitem.png" 
                     format="PNG" />
        </imageobject>
        <!--
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/orage_desktop_menuitem.eps" format="EPS" />
        </imageobject>
        -->
        <textobject>
          <phrase>
            For starting &app; from the desktop menu: "Office" and then click
            on "Orage".
          </phrase>
        </textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>

  <para>
    When you run &app;, you will first see the calendar window appearing.
  </para>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-calendar-window">
  <title>The calendar window</title>
  <figure id="default-calendar-fig">
    <title>Default Calendar window</title>
    <screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/default_calendar.png" format="PNG" />
        </imageobject>
        <!--
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/default_calendar.eps" format="EPS" />
        </imageobject>
        -->
        <textobject>
          <phrase>
            The calendar window.
          </phrase>
        </textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>

  <para>
    The calendar window provides you a menu bar giving access to different
    functions. 
    Below that is a standard calendar showing the month, the year, day names 
    and week numbers. At the bottom there is small window showing active 
    TODOs and EVENTs on the selected day. (Empty parts are not shown.)
  </para>

  <sect2 id="calendar-menu-bar">
    <title>The menu bar</title>
    <para>
      The menubar contains four menus: File, Edit, View and Help.
    </para>

    <sect3 id="calendar-file-menu">
      <title>The File menu</title>
      <figure id="calendar-file-menu-fig">
        <title>File menu in the calendar window</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/orage_calendar_file_menu.png" 
                         format="PNG" />
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
              <phrase>
                The File menu in the calendar window.
              </phrase>
            </textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The file menu contains four items:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          New: start an 
          <link linkend="orage-appointment-window"> appointment window</link> 
          for creating a new appointment;
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          Exchange data: creates window where you can do file level operations
          to Orage data. (1) import and export appointments between
          Orage and operating system files or 2) rename Orage files or 3) add 
          and remove foreign calendar files.);
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          Close: hide the calendar window but keep Orage running in the 
          background;
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          Quit: end Orage;
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 id="calendar-edit-menu">
      <title>The Edit menu</title>
      <figure id="calendar-edit-menu-fig">
        <title>Edit menu in the calendar window</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/orage_calendar_edit_menu.png"
                         format="PNG" />
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
              <phrase>
                The Edit menu in the calendar window.
              </phrase>
            </textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The Edit menu gives you access to the settings window, which will be
        explained later.
      </para>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 id="calendar-view-menu">
      <title>The View menu</title>
      <figure id="calendar-view-menu-fig">
        <title>View menu in the calendar window</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/orage_calendar_view_menu.png"
                         format="PNG" />
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
              <phrase>
                The View menu in the calendar window.
              </phrase>
            </textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The View menu has three choices:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          View selected date: show the event list of currently selected date;
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          View selected week: show the day window starting from current day;
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          Select today: set calendar's selected day to be today;
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>

    <sect3 id="calendar-help-menu">
      <title>The Help menu</title>
      <figure id="calendar-help-menu-fig">
        <title>Help menu in the calendar window</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/orage_calendar_help_menu.png"
                         format="PNG" />
            </imageobject>
            <textobject>
              <phrase>
                The Help menu in the calendar window.
              </phrase>
            </textobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>
      </figure>
      <para>
        The Help menu has also two choices:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          Help: show this help file;
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          About: show information about the version and authors and license;
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect3>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="calendar-window">
    <title>The calendar</title>
    <para>
      Calendar view presents you one month, which you can change by pressing
      the arrow beside the month name or the year number or using the mouse 
      wheel.
      Days where you have appointments or where you have ending TODO are
      marked as bold. One day is always selected and shown with a block.
      You can change the selected day by single clicking any day number.
      Double clicking a day number causes event list window for that day to be
      activated.
    </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="calendar-todo-window">
    <title>The TODO list</title>
    <para>
      The bottom window lists your active TODOs. You can scroll to see
      them all. Red means the TODO is late (due date has passed). Blue means 
      that the TODO is active (start time has passed, but you still have time
      before the due time passes). And black means a future TODO.
      You can edit TODOs by double clicking the row. All rows have tooltips,
      which show more details about the TODO.
    </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="calendar-events-window">
    <title>The EVENT list</title>
    <para>
      Below the TODO list you see your events from the selected date.
      Check the tooltip for more details of the event. Also events can be 
      edited by double clikcing them.
    </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-eventlist-window">
  <title>The event list window</title>
  <figure id="orage-eventlist-fig">
    <title>Orage event list window</title>
    <screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/orage_eventlist.png" format="PNG" />
        </imageobject>
        <textobject>
          <phrase>
            The event list window.
          </phrase>
        </textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>
  <para>
    The event list (or appointment list as it is also called) window shows all
    activites that you have reserved for the day (date is shown in the window
    heading in your locale format).
    On top of the window you have menu and buttons to do actions.
    This is your main activity window and you may want to keep it up all the
    day and even make it to appear on all workspaces or to be always on top
    of other windows.
  </para>

  <sect2 id="event list-action-bar">
    <title>The button bar</title>
    <para>
      There are ten activity buttons in the button bar from left to right:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        New: start an <link linkend="orage-appointment-window">
        appointment window</link> for creating a new appointment for this day;
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Duplicate: also start an <ulink url="#orage-appointment-window">
        appointment window</ulink> for creating a new appointment for
        this day. But do not start from scratch, but copy all values
        from the active row in the appointment list below. Note that
        if you do not have any rows selected from the event list, this
        button does not do anything (but gives a warning);
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Delete: remove all selected appointments. There is no undo, so be 
        carefull with this button! Before removing anything Orage asks for 
        your verification.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Back: show previous day; 
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Today: show today; 
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Forward: show next day; 
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Refresh: redisplay this date;
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Find: activate the search tab;
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Close: close this window; 
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Dayview: start day list window;
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="eventlist-tabs">
    <title>The tabs</title>
    <para>
      Each of the four tabs selects the type of appointments to show. 
      There may also be extra selections possible depending on the tab. 
      You can select tab by clikcing it or by using the mouse wheel. 
      Let's check each tab:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        Event: the event tab shows all EVENT type appointments happening on 
        this day. It is possible to see more than one day in this tab 
        by setting "Extra days to show" number to larger than 0. Each number
        shows one more day. (It causes the Time column in the event listing 
        to show also the date.)
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Todo: shows your active TODOs similarly than in the main calendar
        window. Only active ones are shown. If you want to see old TODOs,
        you need to find them in Search tab.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Journal: lists your notebook entries starting from certain date.
        Default start date is one year back and you can not change the 
        default setting.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Search: enter a free text, which is searched from all the appointments.
        Usually the search is case independent, but for some utf8 characters 
        Orage switches to case sensitive search method. This happens if the 
        length of the string is different in upper case compared to lower case
        (for example German language double s causes this).
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="eventlist-appointments">
    <title>The appointment list</title>
    <para>
      The list shows all appointments satisfying the conditions and tab type.
      Scrollbars will appear if there are more lines or longer lines than 
      what fits into the window. You can edit any appointment by double 
      clicking the row. Note that each repeating appointment is shown only 
      once (=first time) instead of everytime it happens in the specified days.
      Each line has three fields:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        Time: the starting and ending times of the appointment (the format
        varies depending on tab and appointment). All times are always shown
        in our local timezone. It is possible to define special whole day
        appointments and they have a text "All day" instead of real start and
        end times. Rows appear in start time order.
        +sign in front of the time means that the appointment started on some
        previous day and correspondingly +sign at the end of the time means
        that appointment continues and ends later than the selected day.
        If the Event tab shows today, there are few extra formattings used:
        When the event has passed, it is overstriked. Currently active 
        events are shown with blue colour and future events are bold. 
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Flags: gives information about the appointment. If your appointment
        has a category which has been associated with a clour, flags field has
        that colour background. (Note that the explanations are visible as
        a hint when you move your cursor into the appointment list.)
        There are five flags in order:
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            Alarm: what kind of action happens when alarm time passes.
            <keycap>n</keycap> means no alarm has been defined.
            <keycap>A</keycap> means that visible window is raised.
            <keycap>S</keycap> means that sound is played.
            (If both visual and sound alarm is defined, S is shown)
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            Repeat: how often is that appointment happening.
            <keycap>n</keycap> means no repeating so that this event only
            happens once. 
            <keycap>D</keycap> means daily repeat,
            <keycap>W</keycap> weekly, 
            <keycap>M</keycap> monthly and
            <keycap>Y</keycap> yearly.
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            Type: what kind of reservation is this. Two options:
            <keycap>f</keycap> means free so that the action is not reserving
            the time and it is possible to schedule more appointments at the
            same time and respectively 
            <keycap>B</keycap> means busy, so that
            nothing else can be done at this time.  Note that current
            version of &app; does not enforce these and the flag is only as a
            comment (in the future this may be enforced).
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            File: where this appointment is stored.
            <keycap>O</keycap> means it is in the standard active Orage file,
            <keycap>A</keycap> in the archive file. (The appointment is
            automatically unarchived if it is edited.). Archived appointments
            can only be found in the Search and Journal tabs.
            <keycap>F</keycap> appointment is in foreign file; in other words
            it is not native Orage appointment.
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            Appointment type: 
            <keycap>E</keycap> for EVENT,
            <keycap>T</keycap> for TODO and
            <keycap>J</keycap> for JOURNAL.
            This flag is usefull only in search tab since the tab name
            informs the type in other tabs.
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Title: the heading of the appointment. Note that the whole title is
        shown, so you may want to avoid using too long titles to keep the view
        cleaner.
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-daylist-window">
  <title>The day list window</title>
  <figure id="orage-daylist-fig">
    <title>Orage day list window</title>
    <screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/orage_daylist.png" format="PNG" />
        </imageobject>
        <textobject>
          <phrase>
            The day list window.
          </phrase>
        </textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>
  <para>
    The day list window shows all events that you have reserved for the
    next days. Default is to show 7 days, but you can change that and see
    up to 40 days at once.
    On top of the window you have menu and buttons to do actions.
    This is another form of your main activity window and more usefull than
    event list window if you want to find room for your new events or see your
    agenda and free time from longer perod than one day.
  </para>

  <sect2 id="daylist-action-bar">
    <title>The button bar</title>
    <para>
      There are six activity buttons in the button bar from left to right:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        New: start an <link linkend="orage-appointment-window">
        appointment window</link> for creating a new appointment for this day;
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Back: start listing one day earlier; 
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Today: change start day to be today; 
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Forward: start listing one day later; 
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Refresh: redisplay the window;
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Close: close this window; 
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="daylist-parameters">
    <title>The parameters</title>
    <para>
      Below the buttonbar are the two settings. You can change the
      start day of the day list and the number of days shown.
    </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="daylist-list">
    <title>The day list</title>
    <para>
      Biggest part of the window is the day list area. You can click the 
      header of the day to open 
      <link linkend="orage-eventlist-window">event list window</link>
      for that day. First line contains full day events when defined. The other
      lines contain events that you have scheduled. Each event has tooltip
      which include appointment details. You can update the event by double
      clicking it. Events are placed on the start time row and even if the 
      length is several hours, the event is only visible on single row. If
      the event is taking time (availability=Busy), there is vertical line
      in front of it showing its length. These lines show how full your
      calendar is and makes it easier to find free time quickly. If more than
      one events starts at the same hour, they all are added to the same row /
      column after each other and the reservation line is the sum of them.
    </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-appointment-window">
  <title>The appointment window</title>
  <para>
    The appointment window is used to add, edit and delete appointments.
    It is the most complex window in &app;, but most fields still have good
    default values and are not mandatory. It has button bar (All actions are
    also available in menus above the buttons) and three tabs controlling
    basic settings and alarms and recurrence settings.
  </para>

  <sect2 id="appointment-action-bar">
    <title>The button bar</title>
    <para>
      There are 5 activity buttons in the button bar from left to right:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        Save: store the appointment to the orage system. This causes
        also data validity checking.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Save and close: like Save, but also closes the window.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Revert: undo all changes done after previous save. Note that
        this button is active only after data has been changed.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Duplicate: start creating new appointment and copy all values
        from the current activity into it. The new appointment is not created
        until you press <guibutton>Save</guibutton>.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        Delete: remove current appointment permanently from orage
        system.
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="appointment-general-tab">
    <title>The general tab</title>
    <figure id="orage-appointment-fig">
      <title>Orage appointment window - general tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_appointment.png" format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The appointment window.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      In this tab, you define the contents of the appointment.
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Type</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Orage can handle three types of appointments: 
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              Event is something that happens sometimes. It has start and 
              end time. This is the most common appointment type and you 
              actually can handle all cases with this, since it also is the 
              most flexible type. So if you are not sure what type to choose, 
              Event is your best bet. Events either reserve your time 
              (Availability=Busy) or are free which means this event does not
              take time from your schedule. 
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              Todo is some action that you need to complete. It
              usually has a start time and due time when it has to be finished.
              It has no end time, which is replaced by the due time. You can
              also use duration similarly than with events. Todos have no 
              availability, but instead they have completed time. After you
              set the completed time, the todo is done and is removed from 
              lists visible in main calendar and in todo appontment tab. 
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              Journals are just notes. They do not have end times nor
              availability. It is not possible to add alarm or recurrency for
              journals.
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Title</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            The title of the appointment. It appears in the event list
            and also in the alarm window and is listed at the header of this
            window. It should be a rather short summary of the appointment.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Location (Event and Todo)</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            This field should describe where the event happens. It can
            be for example Home or Office or Paris depending on what kind of
            appointment you have. It is also possible to leave it empty. &app;
            is not using it in any special way, nor is it visible anywhere 
            else than here. Journals do not have location.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term id="all-day-event">All day event</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Selecting this checkbox causes so called whole day appointment
            to be defined. These do not have start nor end time defined, but
            it is possible that the event lasts several days. Start time is
            assumed to be the beginning of the day at 00:00 and end date
            at the last day at 24:00.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Start</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Defines the start time of the appointment. First, press the    
            date button and choose the date from the calendar. After that
            you set the hour and minute using either your mouse wheel or
            clicking the small arrows. It is also possible to type the
            numbers directly to the fields. Hours go from 0 to 23 (24 is not
            allowed value).
          </para>
          <para>
            The last button is timezone. Default value for new
            appointments is your current timezone, which you have set in the
            preferences. It is recommended to use real timezones instead of
            floating. You should not mix floating with real timezones although 
            it is possible. Floating means that time is not bound to any
            timezone, but varies according to current settings. Modifying
            either the default timezone or start timezone may cause floating
            values to change.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>End (Event)</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Similar to Start, but defines naturally the ending time. Note
            that start and end timezones may be different (for example when
            you schedule a meeting in abroad you can set the starting time in
            your local timezone and the rest of the timings in the destination
            timezone).
            <link linkend="orage-eventlist-window"> Event list window</link>
            always shows times in your local time. Only events have end time.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Due (Todo)</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Similar to End, but defines the time where the todo should be 
            completed. Only todos have due time.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Duration (Event and Todo)</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Often it is easier to set the appointment duration instead of
            ending (or due) time. You can do that by marking the first box 
            here. It is not possible to have both end/due time and duration 
            at the same time, so end/due time setting will be unavailable
            after you select duration.
            Maximum duration is 1000 days, which is almost three years. Note
            that although the minute selection jumps 5 minutes at a time, you
            can manually enter any number.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Availability (Event)</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            What kind of reservation is this. There are two possiblities:
            <emphasis>Free</emphasis> means that the action is not reserving
            the time and it is possible to schedule more appointments at the
            same time and respectively <emphasis>Busy</emphasis> means that
            nothing else can not be done at this time.  Note that current
            version of &app; does not enforce these menings and the flag is
            only as a comment (in the future this may be checked).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Completed (Todo)</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            By selecting the Done box you mark this todo as done. The completed
            time can then be set. Format is similar to other times (like 
            Start). Only todos have completed time.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Categories</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Free format text, which you can use to categorize your appointment.
            It is also possible to create a list of categories and associate
            those to colours. You can then pick one of those and get your
            appointment to be show with that colour in the event list window.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Note</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Free format text, where you can and should explain more
            the appointment. It is shown in the alarm window. Scrollbars
            appear when needed.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="appointment-alarm-tab">
    <title>The alarm tab</title>
    <figure id="orage-appointment-alarm-fig">
      <title>Orage appointment window - alarm tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_appointment_alarm.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The appointment alarm tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      In this tab, you define the alarm for the appointment. &app; supports 
      three kinds of alarms: window, sound and procedure, but they all happen
      at the same time. It is possible to define only one alarm time for each
      appointment. To cause an alarm you need to do two things: You have to
      define alarm time and select alarm type. By default alarm happens 5
      minutes before the appointment start time. Default alarm is Orage
      window without sound.
    </para>
    <para>
      Alarm time is set if any of the alarm timing numbers is non zero (in
      other words there is no special flag to set alarm; just define the time
      for it. This also prevents setting alarm to happen exactly at the
      appointment start/end time).  You need explicitely select each alarm type
      by crossing the Use box. If you do not choose any alarm types, the alarm
      does not happen.
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Alarm time</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Define how much earlier or later the alarm happens. If all numbers
            are zero, no alarm is raised for this appointment. The last field
            defines what these alarm offset numbers mean. You can define alarm
            to happen based on start or end time of the appointment and also
            if it happens after or before the time. Default is to alarm
            before the start time of the appointment. But specially for todos
            it is often more usefull to raise alarm before the due (=end) time.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Persistent alarm</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            When &app; is not running (for example if your computer is shutdown)
            alarms can't happen. If you want to get reminders after &app;
            starts again, you need to set the alarm as persistent. By default
            alarms are just lost.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Sound</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Define the sound file to be played when the alarm fires.
            Leaving this empty disables sound alarm. Remember to define the
            actual play command in the
            <link linkend="orage-preferences-window">preferences dialog</link>.
            You should also test that your system can play the filetype you
            choose there. Simply start a terminal and test it using the
            command you specified and the sound file.
          </para>
          <para>
            By default alarm sound is played only once, but you can make it
            repeated by choosing the box next line. You can also define how
            many time it is repeated and what is the interval. Be carefull
            to set the interval longer than the length of the sound since
            &app; does not wait for the previous sound to end before starting
            the next sound after the interval.
            Note that there is a silence button in visual alarms, so that you
            can stop the noise, but that only prevents the next play to happen,
            it does not interrupt currently playing alarm, which you should
            remember when using long lasting soundfiles.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Visual</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            &app; can show two kinds of internal visual alarms. Orage window
            is a small alarm window showing the heading and note text. 
            Notification is more fancy notification using libnotify. You need
            to have libnotify installed before you can define this kind of
            visual alarm. <command>orage -v</command> shows if you have
            libnotify support included.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Procedure</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            This makes it possible to use external alarms. You can run any
            operating system command or script. Common use for this is sending
            email.
          </para>
<!--  fixed now to use system, so this works now 
          <para>
            Note that &app; can not handle normal linux redirection. So to send
            email you can not set command to: 
            <command>mail -s hi first.last@address &lt; send_this_file.txt
            </command> because &lt; is not interpreted as redirection of 
            standard input, but it is normal parameter instead. You need to 
            write a shell script to do this and give the file name as a 
            parameter to your script.
          </para>
-->
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Default alarm</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can either set alarm back to default options or you can store
            current settings to be default alarm for all new appointments.
            There is only one default alarm, which applies to all appointments.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="appointment-recurrence-tab">
    <title>The recurrence tab</title>
    <figure id="orage-appointment-recurrence-fig">
      <title>Orage appointment window - recurrence tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_appointment_recurrence.png"
                     format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The appointment recurrence tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      In this tab you can define repeating appointments. Often it makes
      sense that the same appointment happens every day or every month instead
      of creating a new appointment for each event. Note that &app; does not 
      support exclusions (like you would like to skip holiday period from you
      work related appointments), so you have to end the whole recurrency
      and enable it again after it need to resume. &app; also misses the 
      possibility to modify only one specific event from a recurring set. All
      changes affect the whole set of appointments.
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Complexity</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Default is Basic and that makes it possible to define frequency 
            and limit of the appointment only. Often that is enough and these 
            settings are very easy and fast to do even if you are not familiar 
            with calendars and alarms. Selecting Advanced gives you more 
            possibilities and makes it possible to build complex recurrent 
            appointments like for example:
            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                Every Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday and Friday.
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                Last Tuesday on every second month.
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Frequency</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            This is the base repeating period. Default is no repeat (=None)
            and other possibilities are daily, weekly, monthly and yearly.
          </para>
          <para>
            The next selection makes it possible to easily skip some periods.
            Default value is 1 and it means every time as specified in the 
            Frequency selection. 2 means every second time and 3 every third
            time etc. For example if you want to schedule your meeting to
            happen every third week, select Frequency = Weekly and set Interval
            to 3. (Starting time is selected in the 
            <link linkend="appointment-general-tab"> General tab</link> 
            and next event happens exactly 3 weeks from that)
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Limit</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            &app; allows you also to limit the repeating count:
            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                Repeat forever: this is default and does not limit the
                number of occurrences at all.
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                Repeat n times: the appointment is scheduled exactly n
                times. After that it ends (but is not removed).
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                Repeat until date: you can select the last date when this
                event happens. Note that it still happens normally during this 
                date.
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Weekdays (Advanced)</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Default is that all days are checked, which means that the event
            happens normally every day. By removing any check, you prevent 
            the appointment to happen on that day. In other words, your 
            appointment only happens on checked weekdays. The most natural
            usage of this is to use it with Frequency = Daily. You may want
            to have a chat meeting for example each Monday and Wednesday. You
            can do this by selecting Frequency = Daily and by checking only
            Weekdays Mon and Wed. 
          </para>
          <para>
            Selecting Weekly or Monthly actually causes the same thing. 
            Deselecting any weekday for weekly or monthly or yearly repeating
            appointments causes all the remaining weekdays to become selected 
            even though the original repeating selection only selects one day 
            from the period. This is needed so that it is possible to schedule 
            for example a meeting to happen every second week on Tuesday and 
            Friday (Frequency = weekly, Interval = 2, Weekdays = Tue and Fri).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Which day (Advanced)</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            This setting can only be used for monthly and yearly repeating
            events. It can be used to select which weekday from the month or
            year is selected. For example if you want to schedule your
            meeting to happen on the first Tuesday of every month, you can first
            select Frequency = Monthly and then check only Tuesday from Weekdays
            and finally set this "which day" number to be 1 (choose the number 
            located below Tuesday). Negative numbers count backwards starting 
            from the end of period and zero means that this setting is not used.
            Frequency = Yearly, weekdays = Thursday only clicked and which say =
            -2 means second last Thursday of the year.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-exchangedata-window">
  <title>The exchange data window</title>
  <para>
    The exchange data window is used to control physical files of &app;.
    It is possible to import files having calendar data or just use those
    files as they are (foreign). It is also possible to export appointments
    from &app; to operating system files and change the names of &app; data
    files.
  </para>

  <sect2 id="exchange-impexp-tab">
    <title>The import export tab</title>
    <figure id="orage-exchange-impexp-fig">
      <title>Orage exchange window - import/export tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_exchange_impexp.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The exchange data import export tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Import</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Enter the name of the file which you want to copy into &app;.
            You can do several files in a row by separating names with comma.
            After you hae the file name in place, press Save and &app; reads
            the contents in. After the file has been imported, those 
            appointmenst are part of &app; and can't be differentiated or
            put back into the file.
          </para>
          <para>
            You can also import foreign files from the operating system using
            command line. This feature can be used to import ical files
            directly from the web by telling the browser (like firefox) that
            the action is to start &app;
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Export</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Enter the name of the file where you want &app; to write
            appointments. You can choose either all appoinments or just a
            list of ids. Pressing save causes the appointments to be read and 
            written to the external file. (The appointments are are not
            deleted from &app; but are kept in it also.)
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Archive</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can either revert all archived appointments back to the main
            &app; file or force archiving. It is good idea to revert archive
            if you do exports since export does not look data from archive
            file.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="exchange-oragefiles-tab">
    <title>The orage files tab</title>
    <figure id="orage-exchange-oragefiles-fig">
      <title>Orage exchange window - orage files tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_exchange_oragefiles.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The exchange data orage files tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Orage files</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            It is possible to relocate and rename both active &app; file
            and the passive archive file. Pressing save does the actual action.
            There are 3 options for these actions:
            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                Rename: the safest choice. It only updates the file name in
                &app; internal structures. It does not touch operating system
                files at all. The new file has to exist before this operation
                can be done. First copy the file in you operating system
                and then you can change the name.
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                Copy: another safe choice. File is copied first into the new 
                place followed by the internal rename described above.
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                Move: File is moved first into the new place followed by the
                internal rename described above. Note that the original file
                does not exist in the original place anymore after this change.
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="exchange-foreign-tab">
    <title>The foreign files tab</title>
    <figure id="orage-exchange-foreign-fig">
      <title>Orage exchange window - foreign files tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_exchange_foreign.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The exchange data foreign files tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Foreign files</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            &app; can include and maintain other than its main data file.
            It is possible to add (and remove) so called foreign files. They
            behave similarly than base data file, but they remain isolated, 
            so that it is easy to move them back to the original system
            where they came from. This is mainly meant to be used when you
            need to maintain your calendar also in other than &app;. Sometimes
            it is good idea to mark the file as read only, which prevents
            you from modifying any of the appoinments in the corresposnding
            file. (Orage uses some private ical components, which are not
            necessarily understood by the other system, so updates may cause
            problems for the other tool.)
          </para>
          <para>
            You can also add foreign files from the operating system using
            command line.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-preferences-window">
  <title>The preferences window</title>
  <para>
    The preferences window is used to enter initial values for &app;.
    You can define for example several display options, how old appointments
    should be archived and what is the play command to be used for playing
    sound alarms and also you can set the local timezone for &app;.
  </para>

  <sect2 id="preferences-main-tab">
    <title>The main tab</title>
    <figure id="orage-preferences-main-fig">
      <title>Orage preferences window - main tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_preferences_main.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The preferences main tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Timezone</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You should always set the default timezone for &app;. It is
            possible to use also floating times, but then all times should be
            in floating form. It is a bad idea to mix floating and timezone
            times. Floating times tend to move to follow any timezones they
            see...
        </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Archive threshold</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            &app; does not delete appointments automatically, so usually your
            calendar file grows bigger and because of that &app; gets slower
            and takes up more memory from the system. Enabling automatic      
            archiving causes old appointments to be moved from the active
            calendar file to passive history file after the selected time.
            This helps to keep the active file smaller and the application in
            good shape. Archiving is enabled by setting the threshold to other
            than 0 value. Of course it is also possible to manually delete
            appointments, but that removes them permanently and you will not
            be able to find them later.
          </para>
          <para>
            Note that &app; also splits
        <link linkend="appointment-recurrence-tab">recurring appointments</link>
            so that if the original start date is older than threshold, that
            appointment is added to the archive file and the starting date in
            the active calendar file is updated to contain only values more
            recent than the threshold. This also saves time when &app; is
            searching recurrent events.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Sound command</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Here you can define which sound command &app; uses when playing
            sound files. Try testing some common commands like play or aplay 
            from terminal to see what works in your system. You probably do
            not want to use full version of totem or mplayer since they will
            cause a video window also to appear and that most probably is not
            what you want.
          </para>
          <para>
            Basically it is possible to do other than sound commands also since 
            &app; really only starts this program and gives it
            <link linkend="appointment-alarm-tab">the sound file</link>
            as parameter. But this is not the intention of this feature.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="preferences-display-tab">
    <title>The display tab</title>
    <figure id="orage-preferences-display-fig">
      <title>Orage preferences window - display tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_preferences_display.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The preferences display tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      In this tab you can define visibility options for the 
      <link linkend="orage-calendar-window">main window</link> of &app;.
    </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Show borders</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can hide window borders and make the calendar window 
            smaller by unselecting this option. This frees more space to your 
            other applications from your workspace.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Show menu</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            By unselecting this you can leave out the menubar in the top of
            the calendar window.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Show todo list</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can hide TODO list in the main calendar by deselecting this.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Show event list</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can hide EVENT list in the main calendar by deselecting this.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Set sticked</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Show calendar window on all workspaces by selecting this.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Set on top</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Keep calendar window on top of all other windows.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Show in taskbar</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Controls if calendar is visible in the taskbar.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Show in pager</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Controls if calendar is visible in the pager.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Show in systray</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Controls if calendar is visible in the systray. A small 
            window is presented in the systray if this is selected. It is
            recommended that you enable this feature. By clicking this icon
            &app; is toggled visible or hidden. If you do not have &app; in
            the systray, you have two other options to make the main calendar
            window visible: You can either click Orage-clock panel plugin
            or you can start &app; again.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Calendar start</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            It is possible to define that &app; starts in the background or
            as minimized. This option only affects the start of &app;.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="preferences-extra-tab">
    <title>The extra tab</title>
    <figure id="orage-preferences-extra-fig">
      <title>Orage preferences window - extra tab</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/orage_preferences_extra.png"
                       format="PNG" />
          </imageobject>
          <textobject>
            <phrase>
              The preferences extra tab.
            </phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Select always today</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Controls which day is selected after &app; main
        <link linkend="orage-calendar-window">calendar window</link> is hidden
            and comes visible again (for example by clicking orageclock panel
            plugin). Default value is off, which means that previously
            selected day will remain selected. Crossing this causes
            current date always being selected.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Dynamic icon size</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Setting these X and Y sizes to nonzero causes &app; to use dynamic
            icon in taskbar (if you have taskbar and you have selected to use
            taskbar in the Display tab). Dynamic icon includes real month day
            number and also lists &app; in the top and month name at the
            bottom if those fit in. &app; tries to fit all those three pieces
            of information in the available icon size using proper fonts, but
            if there is not enough space, top and bottom texts can be omitted.
            Finally &app; switches to static icon if not even the number fits
            into the icon. Good values to test are 32 (like X=32 Y=32).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Main Calendar double click shows</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can define to start either the event list (=appointment list)
            or the day view window when you double click day numbers in the
            main calendar window.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-undocumented">
  <title>Undocumented Features</title>
  <para>
    Some hidden options allow you to customize &app; behaviour. You can find 
    and change those in <filename>~/.config/orage/oragerc</filename>.
    You must be carefull not to change the format of this file or &app; may
    not start anymore. All the other settings are in the same file.
    Undocumented settings are:
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      Main Window Position: normally you do not want to change this. It is the
      location of <link linkend="orage-calendar-window">calendar window</link>
      in the screen. &app; updates this automatically, so your setting will be
      overwritten.
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      Event Window Size: normally you do not want to change this. It is the
      size of <link linkend="orage-eventlist-window">event list window</link>
      in the screen. &app; updates this automatically, so your setting will be
      overwritten.
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      Logging level: normally you do not want to change this. It can be used
      to control how much information &app; prints to the screen or log 
      file ~/.xsession-errors. Message number are:
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          negative= Debug (Note that special debug code needs to be linked
                  into &app; before these message are in use)
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          0-99    = Message (startup and update modification messages
                  for example)
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          100-199 = Warning
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          200-299 = Critical warning
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          300-    = Error (these cause &app; to abort)
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Ical week start day: Defines what is the first day of week in libical.
        Note, that 
        it is <emphasis>only</emphasis> used in weekly repeating
        appointments. It will <emphasis>not</emphasis> change the
        calendar view anyway. &app; tries is best to find this setting 
        automatically, but if your weekly repeating appointments seem to be
        wrong, you can try to set this. 0 = Monday, 1 = Tuesday...
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="orage-faq">
  <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
  <para>
    Some common questions and answers.
  </para>
  <qandadiv><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>
          Why does my week start on Saturday?
        </para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>
          This really is a problem in your distro. You can check how your
          operating system reports these to GTK+ and hence to &app;, which
          uses strictly gtk calendar widget and does not tune these settings
          itself. Command <command>locale first_weekday</command> shows
          which day is the first day in your system. Usually Sunday is day
          number 1, but that can be changed so check that with command
          <command>locale day</command>, which shows days starting from day 
          number 1. You may try with different LANG enevironment variable
          settings and calendar view in &app; should change accordingly. Log
          a new bug for &app; if you think it is not working correctly.
          Look more information from
          <ulink url="http://bugzilla.xfce.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1237" 
                 type="html">Xfce bug 1237
          </ulink>
          or from
          <ulink url="http://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=215466"
                 type="html">Debian bug 215466
          </ulink>
        </para>
        <para>
          If you are adventurous, you can actually fix these yourself. You
          need to find your locale definition file (like fi_FI or fr_FR). 
          <command>locate</command> is your friend here and helps finding it.
          After that you can check what the setting is: 
          <command>grep first_weekday fi_FI</command> and change that if it is
          wrong and after that you need to recompile your locale database.
        </para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>
          How can I insert my ical file into &app;?
        </para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>
          You can do this with so called foreig files. Add your file as
          a foreign file and &app; will use it. Or you can import the file
          and &app; includes the appointmemts (After this you can not tell
          the difference anymore, so you can not easily move them back to
          where they came form.)
        </para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>
          How can skip my repeating appointment from happening during some 
          period of time?
        </para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>
          This is common requirement. You may for example have work related
          meetings happening every week and when you are on holiday you would
          not like to get alarmed by those nor would you like to see those.
          The iCal standard uses term "Exception Dates" for this kind of
          feature, but unfortunately &app; does not include that feature.
          The easiest way probably is to end those appointment with end date
          and then after the holiday remove the end date again.
        </para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>
          I have found a bug in &app; or would like to see a new feature. How
          can I inform that to the developers?
        </para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>
          You should file a bug into
          <ulink url="http://bugzilla.xfce.org/" 
                 type="html">Xfce bugzilla
          </ulink>
          or send an email to 
          <email>xfce4-dev@xfce.org</email> Xfce development. Please, remember
          to include your full &app; version (preferable the results from
          <command>orage -v</command> or look the version from the about
          window).
        </para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
    <qandaentry>
      <question>
        <para>
          I upgraded to Orage 4.5 from Orage 4.4 and now my old appointments 
          are missing. Are they permanetly lost?
        </para>
      </question>
      <answer>
        <para>
          &app; 4.5 uses different default location for appointments than
          the previous version. And there is no automatic upgrade partly
          because it is safer to leave the old data as it is in case you need
          revert back. &app; 4.5 appointments are not compatible with older 
          &app;. You can however copy your old file to the new place or export
          its contents. You can do that either manually from operating system
          (make sure &app; is not running) or using the interface menus.
          Old default location is 
          ~/.config/xfce4/orage/orage.ics
          and new location is
          ~/.local/share/orage/orage.ics
        </para>
      </answer>
    </qandaentry>
  </qandadiv>
</sect1>
<!--
<appendix><title>An Appendix</title>
<para>...</para>
</appendix>
-->
</article>
